A Guide to the Beverley Family Papers, 1805-1833
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Papers, 1805-1833
Library of Virginia
24541
62 leaves, negative photostats
Beverley Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by J. Motley Booker, Lottsburg, Virginia, 5 October 1956.
Biographical Information
Robert Beverley, Mackenzie Beverley, and Peter R. Beverley were sons of Robert Beverley (1740-1800) and Maria Carter Beverley (1745-1817) of Blandfield in Essex County, Virginia. Robert Beverley was born 12 March 1769 and was educated at Trinity College, Cambridge. He married Jane Tayloe (1774-1816) 26 May 1791 and they had six children. Robert Beverley died May 1843. Peter Randolph Beverley was born 17 October 1780. After living in Bordeaux, France, and Yorkshire, England, he returned to Virginia. He married Lovely St. Martin and they had six children. Mackenzie Beverley was born 3 June 1783 and he married Isabella Gray. They had seven children.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1805-1833, of the Beverley family of Essex and King and Queen Counties, Virginia, consisting of accounts, deeds, deeds of trust, judicial records, plats, receipts, and wills. Deeds are for property in King and Queen County and for slaves. Receipts are for tobacco at Ayletts inspection for rent due Robert Beverley (1769-1843). Judicial records and accounts are from suit of Lunsford Motley, et. al. vs. Robert Beverley in superior court of Essex County. The plats are for property owned B. M. Leland of Northumberland County, Virginia. Papers also include the will of Edwin Motley (d. 1809) of Essex County.
Contents List
- Beverley Family Papers, 1805-1833
  - Deed, 22 November 1805, Peter R. Beverley and Lovely, his wife, to Mackenzie Beverley of King and Queen County for 2,223 acres known as "The Park." Recorded in King and Queen County 8 September 1808., a; 4 leaves
  - Deed, 17 February 1808, Mackenzie Beverley and Isabella, his wife, both of Caroline County, Virginia, to Edwin Motley of King and Queen County for 2,074 acres known as "The Park." Recorded in King and Queen County 13 June 1808, b; 4 leaves
  - Deed of trust, 18 September 1816, William Stuart of King and Queen County, of the first part, William Saunders of Caroline County, of the second part, and Robert Beverley of Essex County, Virginia, of the third part, for slaves. No recordation is shown., c; 4 leaves
  - Will, 5-6 October 1808, of Edwin Motley of King and Queen County. Will probated 3 May 1809., d; 4 leaves
  - Receipts, 1817-1818, for tobacco at Ayletts Inspection for rent due Robert Beverley., e; 14 leaves
  - Suit papers, 1821-1823, in Lunsford Motley, Andrew Motley, Robert Motley, and Silas Motley v. Robert Beverley, Superior Court of Essex County., f; 18 leaves.
  - Accounts, 1816-1818, in relation to suit cited above., g; 8 leaves
  - Plat, April 1833, for estate of B. M. Leland in Cherry Point, Northumberland County, surveyed by Robert Alexander., h; 2 leaves
  - Plat, April 1833, for estate of B. M. Leland called Exeter Lodge, located in Northumberland County, surveyed by Robert Alexander., i; 2 leaves